

Todd Pettee Website Developer

#### Personal Info

521 Turtleback Rd Prescott, AZ 86303

pettee@gmail.com (928) 308-0543

websitesmadesimple.org

#### **Core Skills**

Website Design Customer Service Technical Support Video Production Adobe CC Suite WordPress BuddyPress Education

#### Interests

Japanese Language Rock Climbing Trail Running Photography Surfing Travel Website developer with over 10 years of experience designing, building and maintaining WordPress websites. Self-motivated educator with excellent communication skills and a passion for empowering the average person with the knowledge and tools they need to build and maintain their own website.

## Experience

### Website Developer / Business Owner

Websites Made Simple - Prescott, AZ

01/2010 - Present

- Installed, configured and customized WordPress websites themes and plugins.
- Implemented proactive security measures and cleaned malware from websites.
- Responsible for setup and maintenance of databases, email, DNS and backups.
- Performed on-page and off-page search engine optimizations for websites.
- Produced educational videos teaching how to build a WordPress website.
- Provided technical support via website forums and video comments.

## Customer Service / Technical Support Engineer

07/2006 - 12/2009

PGP Corporation - Salt Lake City, UT

- Provided direct customer service via email and phone support.
- Managed tickets through RightNow Technologies CRM software platform.
- Contributed knowledge base articles to supplement technical documentation.
- Provided tier 1 and tier 2 technical support for entire software product line.
- Deployed and configured desktop, and enterprise server installations.
- Troubleshot and resolved technical issues on Windows, Mac and Linux.

### Classroom Teacher / Performance Supervisor

05/2003 - 06/2006

KTC Foreign Language Institute - Kumamoto, Japan

- Managed thirteen foreign English teachers spread out over two prefectures.
- Prepared and taught lessons to students learning English as a second launguage.
- Performed teacher evaluations and counseled teachers on strengths and weaknesses.
- Organized and facilitated curriculum training and professional development meetings.

#### **Education**

# Bachelor of Arts Elementary/Middle School Education

09/1991 - 05/1995

Cedarville University - Ceddarville, OH

### Certifications

PGP Advanced Administration and Deployment	09/2008
PGP Corporation - Draper, UT	

## CompTIA Network 06/2007

TechSkills - Salt Lake City, UT

Linux/Unix System Administration Certificate 12/2005
University of Illinois and O'Reilly Publishing - Champaign, IL

Japanese Language Proficiency Certificate, Level 2 12/2000

Association of International Education - Tokyo, Japan